Horatio Colony Papers
Horatio Colony Papers
1920-1964
Colony, Horatio, 1900-
9 linear ft.
Papers of the American poet, novelist. Correspondence, book manuscripts and galley proofs.
149715
Biographical History
Horatio Colony (1900-1977) was an American poet and novelist. Born in Keene, New Hampshire, into a family of mill-owners (and grandson of Keene's first mayor), he attended Philips Exeter Academy and Harvard College. He wrote his first play, William Penn's Peace Treaty with the Indians, in seventh grade and his first novel, Free Forester, was published in 1935. He also kept a diary for most of his life, beginning about 1913. His first published poetry volumes, A Brook of Leaves and Birth and Burial, were collections of lyrics, whereas his next three are in the style which might best be described as lyrical narrative. Over his career he published eleven volumes of verse as well as a two-volume set of collected writings.
His house in the town of Keene is today a historical site, the Horatio Colony Museum, and the nearby Horatio Colony Nature Preserve is a direct result of Colony's desire to preserve family land as a wildlife sanctuary.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Horatio Colony Papers consists of manuscripts and published material.
Manuscripts contains a handscript copy of Colony's novel, Free Forester, and handscript, typescript and galley proofs of his poetry books.
Published material includes autographed copies of the following volumes by Mr. Colony: A Book of Leaves, Bacchus and Krishna, Free Forester, The Flying Ones and Young Malatesta.
Arrangement of the Collection
Both series are arranged alphabetically by title.
Subject and Genre Headings
Literature -- American Fiction; Literature -- American Poetry; Colony, Horatio, 1900- -- Archives.; American literature -- 20th century.; American poetry -- 20th century.; Novelists, American.; Poets, American.; Correspondence.; Galley proofs.; Manuscripts for publication.; Poems.; Novelists.; Poets.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Inventory
- Manuscripts
  - Books
    - Free Forester, chapters I - XIV; 14 folders (Box 1)
    - Free Forester, chapters XV-XXII, and incomplete typescript; 9 folders (Box 2)
  - Poetry
    - "Bacchus and Krishna" (Box 2)
    - "Bacchus and Krishna", typescript (Box 2)
    - "The Flying Ones", corrected typescript (Box 2)
    - "The Flying Ones", galley proof (Box 2)
    - "Young Malatesta", author-corrected typescript (Box 2)
- Published material
  - Books
    - A Brook of Leaves (Poetry), 1935 (Box 2)
    - Bacchus and Krishna (Poetry), 1952 (Box 2)
    - Free Forester (Novel), 1935 (Box 2)
    - The Flying Ones (Poetry), 1964 (Box 2)
    - Young Malatesta (Poetry), 1957 (Box 2)